JACQUES PILLET

jacquespillet5@gmail.com http://jacquespillet.github.io

Software Engineer based in Marseille, France, with 7 years of full-time experience in software development, specializing in computer graphics.

Currently working at ScanLAB Projects, an award-winning creative studio in London. Open to opportunities in computer graphics.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Lead Software Engineer

2018 - Present

ScanLAB Projects

London, UK / Marseille, France

- · Led the development of the in-house offline rendering engine (c++, Qt, OpenGL).
- · Designed custom rendering pipelines for XR experiences (Unity, C#, hlsl, Objective-C, Metal).
- · Built technical infrastructures for immersive installations (Python, C++).
- · Designed new architectures for capturing and processing point cloud data (c++, python).
- · Integrated advanced point-based graphics research into production.
- · Key Projects:
 - FRAMERATE: Developed rendering technology and asset management pipeline (c++, python)
 - Eternal Return, Buried in the rock : Created XR Experiences for Oculus Quest, Rift, HTC Vive (Unity, C#, hlsl)
 - Adult Children, Felix's Room, Pistol by Danny Boyle: Implemented real time point cloud capture, processing and rendering tools (C++, OpenGL)
 - Variants by Pierre Huyghe: Built the real-time rendering pipeline for the main screen installation (Unity, hlsl).
 - *Explore Soane Museum website*: Developed of the 3D parts of the website (JavaScript, Three.js, glsl)

Software Engineer 2017 - 2018

Freelance Paris, France

- · Developed Blizaar, a 2.5D visualization of a multilayer graph in the web browser (JavaScript, Three.js).
- · Created a proof of concept augmented reality mobile application for a consulting firm (Unity, C#, hlsl).
- · Led a 3 people team on the development of a mobile app for Epilepsie France (JavaScript).

Software Engineer

2016 - 2017

Modis France

Paris, France

· Developed mobile applications (Java, Apache Cordova).

· Developed website back ends (PHP Symfony) and front ends (Angular)

PROJECTS

Gfx

Developed a low level graphics API abstraction layer in c++, supporting multiple backends (Vulkan, OpenGL, Direct3D11, Direct3D12), and built a simple rendering engine with it.

GPU Path Tracer

Developed an interactive path tracer in c++ running on the GPU with OpenGL or CUDA backends,

and wrote a series of blog posts about it (GLTF Model Loading, PBR materials, volumetric, refraction, subsurface scattering, multiple importance sampling...).

SVGF

Implemented "Spatiotemporal Variance-Guided Filtering" for real time denoising of the previous GPU Path Tracer, added OptiX backend.

Vulkan Renderer

Developed a Vulkan-based renderer, featuring GLTF/Assimp scene loading, forward and deferred renderers, CPU/GPU Compute/RTX path tracing, CPU software rasterizer.

Graphics Experiments

Developped a range of demos for graphics techniques, including Voxel based global illumination, FFT based ocean simulation, Pic-Flip fluid simulation, Clustered/Forward+ rendering, Screen-space reflections, and many others.

Image Lab

Built an image processing tool running mostly on the GPU with OpenGL compute shaders, implementing a wide range of image processing techniques.

EDUCATION

CY Cergy Paris Université

2013 - 2016

MSc in Mathematics and Computer Science, with a major in computer graphics

Cergy, France

Grenoble Ecole de Management

2013 - 2016

MSc in Management

Grenoble, France

SKILLS

- Interpreting creative direction and converting it into practical, efficient solutions
- Solid understanding of computer graphics techniques across a wide range of applications
- Writing high-performance software and optimize code.
- Ability to rapidly learn and effectively work with large code bases
- Programming Languages: C, C++, C#, Python, Java, JavaScript, glsl, hlsl.
- APIs and Frameworks: OpenGL, Vulkan, Direct3D11/12, Cuda, Metal, WebGL, Unity3D, Three.js, Qt5, OpenCV.
- Languages : English, French.

LINKS

- Personnal Website: jacquespillet.github.io
- Blog: jacquespillet.blogspot.com/
- Github: https://github.com/jacquespillet